# Joseph Weil

jweil@ucsd.edu | (916) 500-9662 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-weil-654197282

# **Professional Summary**

Passionate and analytical recent mathematics undergraduate with an interest in applying theoretical knowledge and rigorous coursework in math and physics to develop industry-ready competencies in mechanical engineering. Experienced in applying numerical methods to scientific fields, with the ultimate goal of leveraging problem-solving skills to contribute to interdisciplinary work in mechanical engineering with renewable energy systems.

#### **Education**

## University of California, San Diego

Oct 2020 - Mar 2024

- BS in Mathematics Applied Science
- Minor in German Studies
- GPA: 3.615

# **Relevant Experience**

#### Mathematics LLM Trainer, Outlier – Oakland, CA (Remote)

Apr 2024 - Present

- Assess AI-generated solutions to advanced undergraduate-level mathematical problems from subjects such as calculus and linear algebra
- Meticulously edit and rewrite solutions in LaTeX, ensuring mathematical accuracy and conformity to proper notation

**Quantum ML Intern** – Florence Quantum Labs Startup, San Francisco, CA (Remote)

Sep 2024 – Oct 2024

- Gained foundational knowledge in quantum computing concepts, including qubits, quantum gates, and quantum algorithms, as well as machine learning concepts
- Engaged in fundamental quantum computational programming in the Quiskit framework with the goal of applications to climate forecasting

# **Teaching Experience**

# Mathematics Tutor - Private, San Diego, CA

June 2023 – June 2024

• Prepared and executed detailed and effective learning curricula for several collegiate and pre-collegiate students in differential calculus and college preparatory math

#### **Relevant Coursework**

**Mathematics:** Differential, Integral, Multivariate, and Vector Calculus for Engineering, Differential Equations, Real Analysis, Statistical Methods, and Numerical Analysis: Linear algebra, Approximations, and Nonlinear Equations

**Physics:** Mechanics, Electricity and Magnetism, Optics, Thermodynamics, Fluids, Waves, Relativity and Quantum, Stellar Astrophysics and Black Holes, Atmospheric Dynamics, Ocean Waves

### **Skills and Languages**

- Technology: Python, MATLAB, R, Java, Autodesk Fusion, LaTeX, SQL
- German Language: Intermediate oral and fluent reading/writing
- Additional: Problem-solving, Leadership, Communication and Customer Service

## **Interests**

Independently advancing Python skills and developing personal data science projects utilizing web scraping. Further learning fundamental mechanical engineering subjects such as statics and thermodynamics independently for future study in the field.

# **Additional**

**Certification:** Scientific Computing in Python – FreeCodeCamp

Oct 2024 – Nov 2024

**Extracurricular:** UCSD Collegiate Sailing Team Sept 2021 – Mar 2024